Finding Aid for Elizabeth S. Brater papers, 1989-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Judiciary
  - SB608, Sex Offender Rule 414, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Sex Offender Bills, 2005-2006 (Box 15)
  - Strategic Legislation Against Public Participation (SLAPP), 2005; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - State Court Administrative Office, 2003 (Box 15)
  - Tort/No Fault, 2005 (Box 15)
  - SB633, Tort, Liability, 2003 (Box 15)
  - Violent Video Games, 2005 (Box 15)
- Legislative Files
  The fourth series, Legislative Files, documents Brater's House and Senate legislative activity in areas other than mental health and the environment. Files include bill memos and requests, introduced bills, and research files related to specific bills.
  - Lobbying, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Council of State Governments, Midwestern Legislative Conference, Traverse City, 2007 (Box 16)
  - Sponsored Bills, 1995-1999 (Box 16)
  - Bill Requests, 2005-2006 (Box 16)
  - Bill Requests, 2003-2004 (Box 16)
  - Introduced Bills and Bill Requests, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Press Release for Senate Democrats Environmental Agenda, 2005 (Box 16)
  - SB4, Compulsory School Attendance to Age 18, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Unemployment Benefits, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Dingell Resolution, 2008 (Box 16)
  - Vote by Mail, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Banning Household Batteries and Fluorescent Light Bulbs from Landfills and Municipal Solid Waste Incinerators, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Press Releases and Floor Memos, 1998-1999 (Box 16)
  - Bill Memos, 1995-1999 (Box 16)
  - Fetal Alcohol Syndrome, 1999 (Box 16)
- Other Policy Files
  The fifth series, Other Policy Files, documents Brater's involvement in several other state level policy issues. The issues are Agriculture, Land Use Council, Transportation, Education, Health Care, and Budget and Finance. Files include handwritten notes and research materials on these topics. The series is particularly strong in documenting Brater's positions on taxation issues.
  - Agriculture
    - General Notes, 2002-2006 (Box 16)
    - Mad Cow Disease, 2004 (Box 16)
    - Cattle ID Program, 2006 (Box 16)
    - Drain Code, 2004 (Box 16)
    - Methane Digesters, 2004-2005 (Box 16)
    - Forest Management, 2004-2005 (Box 16)
    - Concentrated Animal Feeding Operations (CAFOs), 2005-2007; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Land Use Council
    - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 16)
    - Notes, 2001; 2003 (Box 16)
    - Notes on Michigan State University Extension's Better deigns for Development in Michigan course, 2001 (Box 16)
    - Notes on Michigan Legislative and Business Leaders forum on Growth Management, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Transportation
    - Railroad Issues, 2008 (scattered) (Box 16)
    - US 23
      - General Information, 2003-2006 (Box 16)
      - Corridor Study Group, 2007 (Box 16)
      - Bus Plan, 2007 (Box 16)
      - Northfield Township, 2002-2003 (Box 16)
  - Education
    - Religion and Education, 1999-2000 (Box 16)
    - K-12
      - General, 1999-2002 (Box 16)
      - K-12 Budget, 2001 (Box 16)
      - Hearing Notes, undated (Box 16)
      - SB4, Compulsory School Attendance to Age 18, 2003 (Box 16)
    - Adult Ed, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Special Ed, 2001 (Box 16)
    - Graduation Requirements, 2006 (Box 16)
    - Higher Education
      - Tuition, 2003 (Box 16)
      - Life Sciences, 2003 (Box 16)
      - University of Michigan Budget, 2004-2005 (Box 16)
  - Health Care
    - General Information, 2000; 2006 (Box 16)
    - Chelsea Hospital, 2002 (Box 16)
    - Long Term Care Medicaid Waiver, 2002 (Box 16)
    - Medicaid, 2002 (Box 16)
    - Insurance, 2002 (Box 16)
    - HB5920 Ethics, 2000 (Box 16)
    - Seniors, 2002 (Box 16)
    - Family Independence Agency, Welfare, 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Budget and Finance
    - Budget, 2003-2004 (Box 17)
    - Budget Presentation, 2003-2004 (Box 17)
    - Michigan Retirement, 2006 (Box 17)
    - Fire Protection Formula, 2003; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Revenue Sharing, 2003-2004; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Securitization, 2005 (Box 17)
    - Taxes
      - General, 2003-2004; 4 folders (Box 17)
      - Democratic Plan, 2000 (Box 17)
      - Expenditures, 2003 (Box 17)
      - Tax Loopholes, 2002-2003 (Box 17)
      - Headlee Override, 2003 (Box 17)
      - Headlee Rollback, 2006 (Box 17)
      - HB5168 Property Taxes, 2003 (Box 17)
      - Income Tax, 2008 (Box 17)
      - Proposition A, 2003 (Box 17)
      - Local Proposition, 2000 (Box 17)
      - SB307, Sales Tax on Services, 2003 (Box 17)
      - Tax Reversion, 1999 (Box 17)
      - Tax Shift, 2004 (Box 17)
      - School Finance Millages, 2003 (Box 17)
      - Single Business Tax, 1995-2006 (scattered); 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Single Business Tax, Detroit Chamber Plan, undated (Box 17)
      - Single Business Tax Plan, 2005 (Box 17)
    - Jobs Today Initiative, 2005 (Box 17)
    - Tobacco Securitization, 2003 (Box 17)
    - Treasury
      - Audit, 2003-2004 (Box 17)
      - Department of Management and Budget, 2003 (Box 17)
      - IT Security, 2003 (Box 17)
- Subject Files
  Subject files, the sixth series contains miscellaneous files on various policy topics from Brater's time in both the House and Senate. The series is split into Senate and House and the files are organized alphabetically by topic.
  - Senate
    - Character Education, 2005 (Box 18)
    - Church/State, 2009 (Box 18)
    - Citizens for a United Michigan, 2003-2004 (Box 18)
    - Eastern Michigan University, 2003-2004 (Box 18)
    - Eminent Domain, 2005 (Box 18)
    - Governor, State of the State, 2004 (Box 18)
    - Health Care Issues, 2003; 2006 (Box 18)
    - Housing, undated (Box 18)
    - Internet II, 2009 (Box 18)
    - Iraq Resolution, undated (Box 18)
    - Labor Issues, 2000-2006 (scattered) (Box 18)
    - Liquor Licenses, 2005 (Box 18)
    - Medicaid, 2005 (Box 18)
    - Millage Rates, undated (Box 18)
    - Michigan Education Savings Program, 2003 (Box 18)
    - Minimum Wage, 2006 (Box 18)
    - Mobile Homes, 2004 (Box 18)
    - Northfield Township, 2003 (Box 18)
    - Pay Day Lending, 2005 (Box 18)
    - Pay Equity, 2004 (Box 18)
    - Pfizer, 2007 (Box 18)
    - Safe House, 2005 (Box 18)
    - Same Sex Marriage, undated (Box 18)
    - Social Security, 2005 (Box 18)
    - Transportation
      - US 23, 2003-2004 (Box 18)
      - Context Sensitive Design, 2002 (Box 18)
      - Michigan Transportation Fund, 2005 (Box 18)
      - US 23 Corridor, Mayor's Proposal, 2005 (Box 18)
      - The Ride, 2003 (Box 18)
    - Stem Cell Research, undated (Box 18)
    - Superior Township, undated (Box 18)
    - Tech Transfer (University of Michigan), 2005 (Box 18)
    - Ten Commandments, 2005; 2007 (Box 18)
    - Terrorism Funding, 2003 (Box 18)
    - University of Michigan
      - Dana Building, 2003 (Box 18)
      - SB1032 Investments, 2004 (Box 18)
      - Police, 2004 (Box 18)
    - Urban Core Mayors, undated (Box 18)
    - Voting Rights, 2004 (Box 18)
    - Washtenaw County
      - Katrina Resources, 2005 (Box 18)
      - Jail, 2003 (Box 18)
      - Washtenaw Intermediate School District, 2002-2004; 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Washtenaw MTA Meeting, 2003 (Box 18)
    - Ypsilanti
      - Ypsilanti Community Utility Authority Incinerator Project, 2003 (Box 18)
      - Presentation, 2005 (Box 18)
      - General Motors Meeting, 2009 (Box 18)
  - House of Representatives
    - Children, 1995-1996 (Box 19)
    - Child Abuse, 1988 (Box 19)
    - Child Care/Head Start, undated (Box 19)
    - Choice, 1996; 2002 (Box 19)
    - Cities Speech, undated (Box 19)
    - "Class Warfare,", 2000 (Box 19)
    - Hillary Rodham Clinton, 1996 (Box 19)
    - Corrections, 1996; 1999 (Box 19)
    - Courts, undated (Box 19)
    - Crime, 1994 (Box 19)
    - Demographics, 1999 (Box 19)
    - Deficit (Federal), 1996 (Box 19)
    - Democratic Party (National), 1996 (Box 19)
    - Democratic Legislative Campaign Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 19)
    - Democratic Notes and Comments, 1995 (Box 19)
    - Demographic Data (Washtenaw County), 1994-1999 (scattered) (Box 19)
    - Economy, 1992; 1994 (Box 19)
    - Economic Conversion, 1994 (Box 19)
    - Education, 1994; 1996 (Box 19)
    - Education (Ann Arbor Public Schools), 1997 (Box 19)
    - Education (Charter Schools), 1995 (Box 19)
    - Education Budget, 1994-2000 (scattered) (Box 19)
    - Education (Title IX) (includes earlier published material), 1993 (Box 19)
    - ERISA, 1995 (Box 19)
    - Firefighters, 1993-1994 (Box 19)
    - Gas Tax, 1996 (Box 19)
    - Gay Rights, 1993 (Box 19)
    - Gender Equity, 1994 (Box 19)
    - Health Care
      - General, 1993-1994 (Box 19)
      - Managed Care, 1996-1997 (Box 19)
      - Single Payer, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Housing, 1994; 2006 (Box 19)
    - Housing Inspections, undated (Box 19)
    - Housing Bureau for Seniors, undated (Box 19)
    - Huron River, 1996 (Box 19)
    - Insurance, undated (Box 19)
    - Insurance Underwriters, 1993-1994 (Box 19)
    - Jobs, 1994 (Box 19)
    - Juvenile Justice, 1996 (Box 19)
    - Labor, 1996 (Box 19)
    - Legislative Scorecards, 1999-2002 (Box 19)
    - Michigan Democrat Party Platform, Environmental Subcommittee, 1996 (Box 19)
    - Minimum Wage, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous, 1995 (Box 19)
    - Mobile Homes, 2003-2004 (Box 19)
    - Privacy
      - Genetics, 1999 (Box 19)
      - Health Identifiers, 1998 (Box 19)
      - Telemarketing, 1996-1997 (Box 19)
      - Drivers, 2000 (Box 19)
    - Prisons, 2000 (Box 19)
    - Proposed Legislation, 1993; 1995 (Box 19)
    - Religious Right, 1993 (Box 19)
    - Republicans, 1995 (Box 19)
    - Revenue Sharing, 1996 (Box 19)
    - Pay Equity, 1994 (Box 19)
    - Pesticides, 1988-1993 (Box 19)
    - Poverty, 1989-1992 (Box 19)
    - Press, 1992-1993 (Box 19)
    - Seniors, undated (Box 19)
    - Subdivision Control, undated (Box 19)
    - Substance Abuse/Dual Diagnosis, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Taxes
      - Property Tax Cut Plan, 1991; 1994 (Box 19)
      - Proposal A, undated (Box 19)
      - Reform, 1994 (Box 19)
    - Tort Reform, undated (Box 19)
    - Transportation Plan, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Welfare, 1997
      - Women's Network for Change, 1995 (Box 19)
      - Women, 1990-1998 (scattered) (Box 19)
      - Women in Government, 1992-1993 (Box 19)
- News Clippings
  The sixth series, News Clippings, documents news coverage of Brater's House and Senate career in local and state level newspapers.
  - Michigan Chinese American News Clippings, 2002-2004 (Box 20)
  - English News Clippings
    - 2003, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - 2004, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - 2005, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - 2006 (Box 20)
    - 2007 (Box 20)
    - 2008, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - 2009 (Box 20)
- Other Office Files
  Other Office Files, the seventh and final series, contains miscellaneous files related to local issues and Brater's career. The series contains a small selection of newsletters she sent to constituents as well as a photograph of the members of the Michigan State Senate during its 125th Anniversary year.
  - Biography, undated (Box 20)
  - Brater Capitol Report, 2003-2005 (Box 20)
  - Newsletters, 2003-2006 (Box 20)
  - Town Hall, 2005 (Box 20)
  - Patriot Act, 2002-2003 (Box 20)
  - Jewish Family Services, undated (Box 20)
  - Michigan State Senate, 125th Anniversary Assembly Photograph, 2004 (Folder UAl)